Guide to the Albert Bandura Papers SC1182
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Albert Bandura papers
1961-2006
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Bandura, Albert
SC1182
16 Linear Feet (14 boxes)
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of article reprints authored by Albert Bandura.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Administrative transfer from the Dept. of Psychology, 2012 & 2016.
Biographical / Historical
Albert Bandura is the David Starr Jordan Professor Emeritus of Social Science in Psychology at Stanford University. He is known as the originator of Social Learning Theory and the theoretical construct of Self-Efficacy. He is perhaps most well-known for the 1961 Bobo doll experiment.
Psychology, Experimental.; Psychology.; Social Psychology; Psychology -- Experiments.; Psychology -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- California -- Stanford.; Bandura, Albert; Bandura, Albert; Bandura, Albert
- Papers
  - Reprints, 1961-1982 (Box 1)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH_2016_144
  - Research, Data & Subject files
    - Awareness, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Psychotherapy, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Ethical Issues, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Psychotherapy notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Job offers, 1961-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - B, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - SR - B, G, M - Social determinant, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - SR - Relative preference, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Training Grant, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - SA - mistaken dependent var., undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Moral judgement, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - CIBA paper, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Psychotherapists anxiety, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Self interest group, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Balue orientations, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - No trial learning, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Analysis of modeling, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Parke chapter, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Vicarious Sr. processes, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Rosenthal article, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Aggregate, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Syntactic style, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - B. Blanchard Ritter, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Media diffusion, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Behavioral psychotherapy, 1967 Mar (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Social learning theory, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Disinhibition of aggression, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Stormy decade, 1964 Jul (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - 254 - Reserve list, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Chance encounters, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Depression - Abrams, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Cardiac SE, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Sports efficacy, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Carroll study, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Types of incentives, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Resistance to Deviation, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Preparedness - Fear, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Zajonc - Feeling thinking, 1984 Feb (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Awareness - CSR, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Aids, 1990 Feb -Jun (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Aids, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Aids - newspapers, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Aids, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Force, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Rome, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - undated, 1997-2005 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Osofsky, 2003 Jun 2 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Osofsky, 2005 Feb (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Terrorism, 2006 Feb 14 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Terrorism, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Intrinsic motivation, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Aggression - definition, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Past experiences, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Cross-cultural aggression, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Catharsis, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Crowding, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Frustrative nonreward, 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - FU questionnaires, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Catecholamine - forms, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Catecholamine - data sheets, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Subject list - IMMUOE, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Consents -spider, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Confidence scales, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Follow up: Scripts, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Fear scales, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Efficacy scales - pre, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Follow up - Efficacy scales, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Behavior test, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Consent, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Therapy checklist, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Consent form, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Master list - phobia, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Causal test, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - unlabeled, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Terrap, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Consent forms, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Condition 2, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Condition 1, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Condition 3, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Condition 4, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Worker profiles, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Code system, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Master - immune, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Consent Agreement, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Consents - CIOFI, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - CIOFIO - consent, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - School efficacy, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - MacArthur Foundation, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Collective efficacy, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - ECCLES, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Schunk forms, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Goal setting forms, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Tobacco, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Data analysis - aggression, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Follow-up questionnaires, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Identification study, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Data: gender constancy interviews, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Follow-up interview, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Questionnaires, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Catharsis, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Unconsious metacognition, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Aggression Bandura, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Mailed questionnaires, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Spencer Grant (old), 1989 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - High low schools, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - CAT - all schools, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Teacher - correlation, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - CRT, 1992 Apr 3 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - CRT, 1991 Jul 16 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Regression Analysis, factor analysis, summary analysis, path analysis, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Implementation, 1992 Mar - Apr (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Rs - CRT, CAT, comp, demog., 1992 Apr 27 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Regression Analysis, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Comer schools, 1991 Aug (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Correlations - CAT, 1992 Jan 21 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - School composition, 1991 Nov - Dec (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Principals, 1991 Dec - 1992 Jan (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Combined cats - 113, 1991 Nov - Dec (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Report analyses, 1992 Apr -Jun (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Teacher demographics, 1991 Dec (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Basic data (SE demog.), 1991 Nov (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Regression analysis (old variables), 1992 May 16-22 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Key analyses, 1992 May 15 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Spenser reports, undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Basic data file, 1992 Apr 13 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Computer program, 1992 Jul 31 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Original data, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - unlabeled, undated (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Key sets 1 2 feat. Inventory data, undated (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Master subject list, undated (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Follow-up questionnaires, undated (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Snake phobia efficacy scales (extras), undated (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Extra forms, undated (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Terrap forms, undated (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Spider study - causal test, undated (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Attitude survey, undated (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Templates, undated (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Phobia forms, undated (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence (incoming) 1 of 4, 1961-1967 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence (incoming) 2 of 4, re: reprints, 1961-1968 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence (incoming) (3 of 4) re: reprints, 1961-1968 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence (incoming) re: reprints, 4 of 4, 1961-1968 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - R R, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - McDonald, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Menclove - VC ext, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Grusec - Sr, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Coding - Grusec, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - R R model reward, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Mahoney - Pigeons, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Jeffery - coding, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Harris, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Perloff - SR - DR, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Modeling - Revelle, 1965 Jun (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Rosenthal - Terapy, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Film - mediated Agg models, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Barab - modeling, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Rosenthal, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Belay Gratific, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Mahoney - Dirks, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Snake tape 3, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Whalen - conflict, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Barab - imitation, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Huston, undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Modeling processes, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Coding - Batiehm, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Comparative test, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - SE - fear, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Chance encounters, 1982 Jul (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Schunk, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Identification, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - B. Reese, Adams, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Reciprocal determinism, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Temporal dynamics, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Grusec, undated (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Goal setting - Cervone, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Self-system, 1978 Apr (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Recycled ideologies, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Exposure, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Lovaas project, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Prototypes of Stimuli, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Conceptual Modeling, 1971 Nov (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Language Learning, undated (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Perceived self efficacy, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - Rebuttal, 2001 Dec (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Recycling misconceptions of Rosemond self efficacy, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - subjective/ objective, undated (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - in search of pure determinants, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - efficacy of participant, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - self efficacy, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - Perceived self efficacy, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 52)
  - Photographs
    - Photographs, undated (Box 4)
  - Objects
    - "No Pain, No Gain" plaque, 1993 Jun (Box 5)
    - Bobo Doll, undated (Box 6)
  - Audiovisual material
    - unlabeled, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b7_01; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 7)
    - The Bing Nursery School Stanford University, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b7_02; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 7)
    - Bobo, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b7_03; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 7)
    - Bobo for Bandura, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b7_04; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 7)
    - Bobo Doll Aggression film, no audio do not use, 1998 Apr; sc1182_2016_144_b7_05; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 7)
    - unlabeled, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b7_06; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 7)
    - unlabeled, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b7_07; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 7)
    - unlabeled, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b7_08; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 7)
    - Practice tape, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b7_09; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 7)
    - an interview with Albert Bandura, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b7_10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 7)
    - An interview with Albert Bandura, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b7_11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 7)
    - An interview with Albert Bandura (1), undated; sc1182_2016_144_b7_12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 7)
    - #1 Snake, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b9_01; 1 film(s) (Box 9)
    - Al- control, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b9_02; 1 film(s) (Box 9)
    - Extra endings, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b9_03; 1 film(s) (Box 9)
    - Aggression Rewarded, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b9_04; 1 film(s) (Box 9)
    - unlabeled, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b9_05; 1 film(s) (Box 9)
    - #2 snake, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b9_06; 1 film(s) (Box 9)
    - Agg self + social, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b9_07; 1 film(s) (Box 9)
    - Adult, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b9_08; 1 film(s) (Box 9)
    - All Endings, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b9_09; 1 film(s) (Box 9)
    - Agg Self-social, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b9_10; 1 film(s) (Box 9)
    - unlabeled, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b9_11; 1 film(s) (Box 9)
    - unlabeled, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b9_12; 1 film(s) (Box 9)
    - unlabeled, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b9_13; 1 film(s) (Box 9)
    - Snake dog duplicate, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b9_14; 1 film(s) (Box 9)
    - Snake control film, Dog Modeling original editing, 1970 June; sc1182_2016_144_b9_15; 1 film(s) (Box 9)
    - unlabeled, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b9_16; 1 film(s) (Box 9)
    - Snake Or, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b9_17; 1 film(s) (Box 9)
    - Agg O-St Social - Self +, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b9_18; 1 film(s) (Box 9)
    - Old Reel 2, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b10_01; 1 film(s) (Box 10)
    - Snake #1, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b10_02; 1 film(s) (Box 10)
    - snake. DU, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b10_03; 1 film(s) (Box 10)
    - 8 mm snake, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b10_04; 1 film(s) (Box 10)
    - unlabeled, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b10_05; 1 film(s) (Box 10)
    - Togetherness, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b10_06; 1 film(s) (Box 10)
    - Dog phobia 16 mm film, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b10_07; 1 film(s) (Box 10)
    - Agression Social + Self, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b10_08; 1 film(s) (Box 10)
    - unlabeled, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b10_09; 1 film(s) (Box 10)
    - Parking space aggression 2/2, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b10_10; 1 film(s) (Box 10)
    - Parking space aggression 1/2, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b10_11; 1 film(s) (Box 10)
    - Rice Media Center "Bandura Film part II", undated; sc1182_2016_144_b10_12; 1 film(s) (Box 10)
    - Rice Media Center "Bandura Film Part I", undated; sc1182_2016_144_b10_13; 1 film(s) (Box 10)
    - Stanford U. Phsy Dept., undated; sc1182_2016_144_b13_01; 1 film(s) (Box 13)
    - MM2, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b13_02; 1 film(s) (Box 13)
    - unlabeled, 1965 Nov 1; sc1182_2016_144_b13_03; 1 film(s) (Box 13)
    - Control film, 1964 Nov; sc1182_2016_144_b13_04; 1 film(s) (Box 13)
    - Inside playpen - feeding dog, 1965 Nov 5; sc1182_2016_144_b13_05; 1 film(s) (Box 13)
    - Milk bottle feeding, 1965 Nov 5; sc1182_2016_144_b13_06; 1 film(s) (Box 13)
    - Rades around playpen, 1965 Nov 1; sc1182_2016_144_b13_07; 1 film(s) (Box 13)
    - feeding cookies, riding cart, milk bottle, 1965 Nov 5; sc1182_2016_144_b13_08; 1 film(s) (Box 13)
    - MM3, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b13_09; 1 film(s) (Box 13)
    - MM4, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b13_10; 1 film(s) (Box 13)
    - Multiple models, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b13_11; 1 film(s) (Box 13)
    - Walk, brush, bottle wigs, 1964 Dec 3; sc1182_2016_144_b13_12; 1 film(s) (Box 13)
    - MM 6, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b13_13; 1 film(s) (Box 13)
    - MM 7, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b13_14; 1 film(s) (Box 13)
    - Inside playpen - sleeping, 1965 Nov 5; sc1182_2016_144_b13_15; 1 film(s) (Box 13)
  - Computer Files
    - CSI Project Hernon Gouet "Betsy", undated; sc1182_2016_144_b8_01; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 8)
    - The Century of the Self, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b8_02; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 8)
    - Albert Bandura Disc no. 00010 "Knowing me, knowing you, 2006; sc1182_2016_144_b8_03; 1 optical disc(s) (CD-R) (Box 8)
    - Powerpointy-presentation Albert Bandura, "Aggression: A social learning analysis" written in German by A. Krohn, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b8_04; 1 optical disc(s) (CD-R) (Box 8)
    - Bandura Aggression + Related Resources video, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b8_05; 1 optical disc(s) (CD-R) (Box 8)
    - Kill Bobo vol. 1 by Michaela Donovan and Rachel Contreras, undated; sc1182_2016_144_b8_06; 1 optical disc(s) (CD-R) (Box 8)
    - the Evolution of Psychotherapy the World's Largest Psychotherapy Conference 5th conference, 2005 Dec 7-11; sc1182_2016_144_b8_07; 1 optical disc(s) (CD-R) (Box 8)
    - Bandura/1 Graphanalia 6509668902, 2000 Jun; sc1182_2016_144_b8_08; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 8)
    - Bandura/2 Graphanalia 6509668902, 2000 Jun; sc1182_2016_144_b8_09; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 8)
    - Bandura/3 Graphanalia, 2000 Jun; sc1182_2016_144_b8_10; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 8)
    - Bandura/4 Graphanalia, 2000 Jun; sc1182_2016_144_b8_11; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 8)
    - Bandura/5 Graphanalia, 2000 Jun; sc1182_2016_144_b8_12; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 8)